<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://rylie.moe/feed_style.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <tabi:metadata xmlns:tabi="https://github.com/welpo/tabi">
        <tabi:base_url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rylie.moe</tabi:base_url>
        <tabi:separator>
            |
        </tabi:separator>
        <tabi:about_feeds>This is a web feed, also known as an Atom feed. Subscribe by copying the URL from the address bar into your newsreader. Visit About Feeds to learn more and get started. It&#x27;s free.</tabi:about_feeds>
        <tabi:visit_the_site>Visit website</tabi:visit_the_site>
        <tabi:recent_posts>Recent posts</tabi:recent_posts>
        <tabi:last_updated_on>Updated on $DATE</tabi:last_updated_on>
        <tabi:default_theme></tabi:default_theme>
        <tabi:post_listing_date>date</tabi:post_listing_date>
        <tabi:current_section>games</tabi:current_section>
    </tabi:metadata><link rel="extra-stylesheet" href="https://rylie.moe/skins/sakura.css?h=2d9c69af51135683e3bd" /><title>lumi's trashcan - games</title>
        <subtitle>my thoughts and rants.</subtitle>
    <link href="https://rylie.moe/tags/games/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://rylie.moe/tags/games/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://rylie.moe/tags/games/atom.xml</id><entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>her tears were my light (2016)</title>
        <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
            <name>lumi</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rylie.moe/blog/her-tears-were-my-light/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rylie.moe/blog/her-tears-were-my-light/</id>
        
            <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;image&#x2F;her-tears-were-my-light&#x2F;header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;her tears were my light Steam header&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a love story between time and space&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Steam description was right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“her tears were my light” is a short visual novel, made for the NaNoRenO 2016
game jam. And when I said short, it was short. All the content is explorable in
about half an hour to an hour of gameplay. Despite its length, it manages to
hold up pretty well, with plenty of cute illustrations and a really nice
soundtrack.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game follows Time, Space and Nil - the three core ideas of the entire
universe, in their love story. It’s rather surreal in some ways, but at the same
time, it gives these very grand and cosmic concepts and their relationship a
very human and emotional touch. Girls kissed. What else more could you ask for?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being Time, a key gameplay mechanic is the ability to rewind time and change the
past. This ability is executed really well, being very intuitive and doesn’t
make it feel complex for the reader. The story is intertwined heavily into this
mechanic as well, so a good execution really made everything feel fluid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, it’s a really cute game, and it doesn’t take up any time to finish. I
think it’s worth the hour spent reading. It’s available for rather cheap too -
find the game on &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nomnomnami.itch.io&#x2F;her-tears-were-my-light&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
or &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;store.steampowered.com&#x2F;app&#x2F;2112520&#x2F;her_tears_were_my_light&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Steam&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        <summary type="html">&quot;her tears were my light&quot; is a short visual novel, made for the NaNoRenO 2016 game jam. And when I said short, it was short. All the content is explorable in about half an hour to an hour of gameplay. Despite its length, it manages to hold up pretty well, with plenty of cute illustrations and a really nice soundtrack.</summary>
        </entry><entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Bad Game Design: Kaneshiro and Okumura&#x27;s Palaces in Persona 5 Royal</title>
        <published>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
            <name>lumi</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rylie.moe/blog/bad-game-design-persona-5-royal/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rylie.moe/blog/bad-game-design-persona-5-royal/</id>
        
            <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post contains spoilers for Persona 5 Royal! If you haven’t played the
game yet, I suggest you stop reading to avoid spoilers, else, proceed at your
own caution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I decided to pick up Persona 5 Royal, as I broke my controller and…
Persona 4 Golden on a keyboard felt horrible (this probably needs its own blog
post…) so I put it on pause for now. Fast-forward a few weeks later and I’m 60
hours into it. I’ve been enjoying the game &lt;strong&gt;a whole lot&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, but there are points
where I feel like the game is out to annoy me. I’ve still got half the game left
to go - but these will be my thoughts up to this point, for Kaneshiro’s bank and
Okumura’s spaceport.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;kaneshiro-s-palace&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#kaneshiro-s-palace&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: kaneshiro-s-palace&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Kaneshiro’s Palace&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third palace in the game. This is probably the first instance that I felt
like the game was a bit annoying. The palace itself is fine thematically, and
the OST was really nice too. But, despite all that, the mechanics in this palace
felt &lt;em&gt;so wrong&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main puzzle within the palace involves the security system, where you have
to decode a 4-letter word into numbers to progress. Each letter corresponds to a
number, and you have to go around the palace collecting torn pages from
Kaneshiro’s journal to form the cipher.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page-collection part itself is fine, running around the palace to find the
pages is pretty simple. Each page is in a &lt;em&gt;very visible&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; piggy-bank-shaped
container. I was stuck for like… 20 minutes finding myself missing a page, but
that was mostly my fault for overlooking a container right next to a room
entrance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the annoying part about this is how the hints are basic arithmetics, but
there are so many of them you are basically &lt;em&gt;required&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to have a notepad of some
sort to solve for all the letters involved. But, alas, it’s fine, I’ll let this
one slide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst part about this palace has to be how you have to do this a total of
&lt;strong&gt;three times&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. And for &lt;em&gt;every corridor&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; you clear while finding each keypad,
there are no safe rooms - there’s only one at the start of the vault. If you end
up failing a single encounter randomly (god bless this game’s RNG!), that means
you’re restarting from the start of that corridor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I can see how this is just the game being “difficult” and punishing
failure, but it’s just slightly annoying how you have to reclear each vault
floor if you accidentally fail a fight. The fights aren’t hard, but it’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
easy to randomly die if you get a stupid effect proc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, I feel like the mechanics of Kaneshiro’s Palace are just slightly
annoying, in the lines of being tedious, but it’s not totally bad. It’s a nice
end to Makoto’s story arc, and I didn’t lose too much time pulling my hair to
finish it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;okumura-s-palace&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#okumura-s-palace&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: okumura-s-palace&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Okumura’s Palace&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaneshiro’s Palace is definitely, definitely, &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; no match for this.
The fifth palace in the game has to be one of the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; designed palaces I’ve
ever seen. It’s so bad we even got subsections for it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;timed-mechanics&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#timed-mechanics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: timed-mechanics&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Timed mechanics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of the mechanics are timed, which technically fits the theme of
“capitalism draining everyone dry”, but it’s just so, so, so annoying. Pathing
through the map involves a bunch of 30-second timed platforms, and you need to
backtrack and re-activate the platforms to progress if you don’t make it in
time. This time passes during fights too, so if you accidentally get an
encounter, have fun backtracking!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yippee, you’ve made it to the end of the palace, and you sent the calling card.
You enter the palace again, fast travel to the last section before the boss
encounter, and you feel like you’re &lt;em&gt;so&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; prepared to do this boss fight. You’re
wrong. You are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ready to do this boss fight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little bit of a cutscene, a 10-minute timer starts, and you’re supposed
to chase after Okumura. You are supposed to run through a Shadow-infested
corridor to catch up to him, and you have to do this in 10 minutes. If you don’t
make it in time, you have to restart from the start of the corridor. This is the
most annoying part of the palace, and it’s just so, so, so frustrating.
Thankfully, the kind developers at Atlus has added the grappling hook to Royal,
and you have a shortcut to skip yourself straight to the boss encounter,
rendering the annoyance of this 10-minute timer to essentially null.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should be it right? Oh dear sweet summer child, you’re getting even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
wrong. The boss fight has a &lt;strong&gt;thirty-minute&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; time limit. “It’s a whopping
thirty minutes!”, I hear you say. Well, let me tell you about the mechanics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;boss-fight-mechanics&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#boss-fight-mechanics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: boss-fight-mechanics&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Boss fight mechanics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okumura sends waves of &lt;strong&gt;four&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; robots of increasing strength to face you, while
he sits in the back and either buffs them or debuffs your party. The robots are
weak to certain elements, and resists everything else. You have met all of these
robots as part of the introductory sequence of the palace, and good luck
preparing for &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you, you have three turns to attack and kill these robots to clear the
“wave”. If you don’t kill them in time, if you dealt even just &lt;strong&gt;a single
point&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of damage to any of them, they would flee and you would fail the wave.
This is probably the part where the game expects you to abuse the hell out of
Baton Passes to maximize damage dealt, but I’m telling you, even on Normal
difficulty, maximum Baton Passes on Haru struggles to take down the last wave of
robots.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This straight up makes it extremely annoying as these robots are super tanky
&lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; they deal a ton of damage to your party as well. With all of this, you can
probably start to see how thirty minutes straight up isn’t enough to clear the
fight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve sat and pulled my hair for at least &lt;strong&gt;three hours&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; doing Okumura’s boss
fight and &lt;em&gt;I still haven’t cleared it&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and I’ve got close to clearing the fight
only &lt;em&gt;once&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;… If this isn’t one of the worst designed boss fights in the game,
I don’t know what is. It frustrates me genuinely because Haru’s arc was getting
really, really good and this horrible boss fight makes it so tedious to go
through, and simply ruins the narration for me purely because how long it takes
to finish it. I’ve also spent at least two hours looking at Reddit posts asking
on how to fight it and a &lt;em&gt;whole lot&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of them is pointing towards abusing
Merciless’ 3x weakness multiplier and a DLC Persona to clear the fight. I’m
&lt;em&gt;very close&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to just doing that, but I’m still holding out hope that I can clear
it without resorting to that. The sheer difficulty of the fight just makes me
reconsider doing NG+ runs as well, but I will see how that goes…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-damn-airlock-puzzles&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#the-damn-airlock-puzzles&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-damn-airlock-puzzles&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
The damn airlock puzzles&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit before the boss fight, you have to go through a series of airlock puzzles
to progress. It’s &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; very clear what you really need to do, other than
toggling the various switches to progress. It’s so annoying that you constantly
need to constantly toggle the map to find out the path you need to take &lt;em&gt;while&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
attempting to grab the third Will Seed. The pathing took me forever since you’re
meant to go in one specific direction. This puts the icing on the cake for how
bad Okumura’s Palace is designed. Thank &lt;strong&gt;god&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; you’re not timed on this
section, or else I would genuinely flip doing this palace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor no-hover-padding&quot; href=&quot;#closing-thoughts&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;link-icon&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Closing thoughts&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’ve learnt to accept Kaneshiro’s bank, Okumura’s spaceport is still
something I genuinely am frustrated about. This really ruined the experience for
this part of the game for me, and it made me feel stuck similar to Yakuza Kiwami
2’s Man in Black fight. But alas, after writing this, I’ll probably spend the
next few hours trying to clear this fight, but this will definitely go down as
one of the worst designed fights I’ve ever witnessed in a JRPG.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still want to make clear that this doesn’t make Persona 5 (Royal) a bad game
by any means! It’s still a truly enjoyable experience overall, and I still don’t
regret the hours I’ve sunken into this game. I really recommend it if you are
interested in turn-based RPGs, or you wanted a good entry point into the Persona
series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        </entry>
</feed>
